Inventory of the Helen L. Johnson Papers 1925-1982
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Helen L. Johnson Papers 1900-19821925-1940
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.305
0.80
Papers of Helen L. Johnson, circa 1925-1940, covering her activities with the Methodist Episcopal Church Woman's Home Missionary Society. Materials include letters addressed to Johnson, photographs, programs, fliers, prayers and religious songs and other ephemera of a religious nature. Geographic areas covered include Ohio, Pennsylvania, Nebraska, and New York State.
Johnson, Helen L.; Methodist Episcopal church. Woman's home missionary society arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 07/17/2009.
Biographical Note
During the late 1920s and the 1930s, Helen L. Johnson was a preacher and missionary for the Methodist Episcopal Church Woman's Home Missionary Society. At one point she was also the national organizer of young people's work of that same society. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Helen L. Johnson.
Scope and Contents
Papers of Helen L. Johnson, circa 1925-1940, covering her activities with the Methodist Episcopal Church Woman's Home Missionary Society. Materials include letters addressed to Johnson, photographs, programs, fliers, prayers and religious songs and other ephemera of a religious nature. Geographic areas covered include Ohio, Pennsylvania, Nebraska, and New York State.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is organized into four series: Programs and Publications; Correspondence; Photographs; and Ephemera.
Additional Information
Related Materials
For papers related to Methodist clergy in Virginia, see James Family Papers (Mss. 81 J23).
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs; Plays (document genre); Printed ephemera; Programs; Religious texts
Topical Term:
Address books.; Hymns.; Methodist Episcopal Church. Woman's Home Missionary Society; Missionaries--United States--20th century.; Pamphlets; Prayers.; Women missionaries--United States.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Programs and Publications, 1900-1982; id59818
  - id59860 (Box 1)
    - Library and Other Micellaneous Cards, 1900-1940 and undated; id59874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Documents Related to Prayer and Religious Songs, 1931-1939; id59861 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Religious Programs, July 18, 1936-September 19, 1982; id59866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church Publication--"From Drawing Room to Living Room", 1936; id59867 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Methodist Church Book--"New Building Nashville", 1952; id59868 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Religious Publications, 1935- 1950; id59869 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Golden Girls Pamphlets, 1934- October 9, 1936; id59870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Queen Esther Pamphlets, Song Book, and Three Act Play, 1936; id59871 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Queen Esther News" Newsletter, December 1939-April 1940; id59872 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters, December 10, 1938-January 2, 1948; id59873 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - id59862 (Box 2)
    - Bible Study Notes, circa 1934; id59863 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Prayer Group, Summer School, and Service Notes, undated; id59875 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Service Outlines, Notes, Undated; id59877 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1927-1940; id59822
  - id59864 (Box 2)
    - Letters to Helen L. Johnson, September 7, 1925-December 24, 1934; id59865 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Helen L. Johnson, April 25, 1938-September 14, 1950; id59880 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letter to Helen L. Johnson--Local Preacher's License, October 12, 1936; id59881 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1936 and undated; id59826
  - id59883 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, Includes Photographs of The Golden Girls, 1936; id59884 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ephemera, 1936 and undated; id59859
  - id59885 (Box 2)
    - Women's Home Missionary Society-- Ribbons, 1926-1936; id59888 (Box 2, Folder 7)